喂
好的
赶紧的
Listo.
车来了
Vámonos!
在这里
In here!
老大在这里  快  快
Jefe! Rápido! Rápido!
推进去  推进去
Entrar, entrar!
他怎么办
What about him?
拜托
Hey, come on.
帮个忙
Por favor.
帮个忙  来救命啊
Help! Oh, c-- Assistance!
这人需要帮助
This man needs help!
可付我薪水的是他
This man pays my salary.
第四季 第十一集
S04E11: Crawl Space
40.23磅
40.23 pounds.
他们回来了吗
Are they back yet?
你有消息吗
Have you heard from anyone?
如果平克曼死了  我就不干了
If Pinkman is gone, I'm done.
听明白了吗  我辞职
Do you understand? I quit.
我刚跟你说过了  40.3磅
I just told you. 40.3 pounds.
40.21磅
40.21.
我连襟
Look, uh, my brother-in-law--
他一直在说要开去工厂化农场看看
he keeps talking about driving out to the factory farm,
我已经
and I have--
尽可能地拖住他了
I have stalled him as long as I possibly can,
但拖到现在
but it's really at the point now
他很可能会找别人带他去的
where he's just gonna find someone else to take him out there.
我不知道那里是否收拾妥当
So I-I don't know if it's been made presentable yet,
但应该由我带他去  对吧
but I should be the one to take him out there, right?
那你能不能帮我通传一声
Can you just run it up the chain of command, then?
有什么可疑的吗
Anything suspicious?
还是没有  沃特
Still no, Walt.
那我们该走了吗
Well, then, should we go?
你有地方要去吗  因为你好像
You got someplace to be? 'Cause that's, like,
问过我三遍了
the third time you've asked me that.
没有  我只是很好奇
No. I'm just curious
下一步怎么办
what the next move is.
我们下三步都是静观其变
Our next three moves is sitting here and waiting.
这工作就是这样  兄弟
This here's the job, buddy.
你知道的
You know,
不像人家有游艇超模什么的
supermodels and speedboats, you know?
有什么贩毒集团的消息吗
Any, uh, cartel news these days?
我总是在报纸上
Seems like I'm always
读到一些零碎的
reading something or other in the paper.
是啊  发生在国内的不太多
Yeah, well, not a lot happening Stateside.
我听说南部发生了一些摩擦  大动干戈
I'm hearing rumblings about some big play down south.
显然死了很多人
Lots of bodies, apparently,
就算是对于贩毒集团而言
even by cartel standards.
等事情浮出水面  我们会有更多消息
We'll know more when the buzzards leave the bones.
我们什么时候该聊聊你的脸色
So when are we gonna talk about your face?
我可不想聊这个  行吗
I don't wanna get into it, okay?
不  这可不行
No, it's not okay.
我连襟一副不屑一顾的态度
My brother-in-law shows up looking like Macho Camacho,
他不觉得我们该讨论一下吗
and he thinks we're not gonna discuss it?
兄弟  如果你有什么烦心事
You know, buddy, if you're in over your head on something,
你不觉得理应找我倾诉吗
don't you think I might be the guy to come to?
我海军航空基地有位老友
You know, one of my old buddies from Glynco--
他嗜好赌博
he had a gambling problem,
但他爱玩刮刮卡
but his thing was scratch cards
而不是二十一点
instead of blackjack.
那愚蠢的混蛋
Dumb Okie bastard.
抵押了自己的汽车去玩连刮卡
Had his car repo'd playing scratch-n-wins.
他现在没事了  他得到了帮助
He's fine now, you know. He got help and all.
但是我知道他戒掉赌瘾的路很是艰难
But I know he got on a ride that was rough to get off of.
我只是说  如果你想聊聊
I'm just saying I'm here, you know,
我随时恭候
if you want to talk about it.
我不想跟你或任何人
I don't want to talk about it
聊什么事
to you or to anyone else.
我不想再为自己辩解了
I'm done explaining myself.
喂  叫你呢
Hey, uh-- Yo.
他还需要继续输血吗
You think he needs some more blood?
血在冰箱里
It's in the refrigerator.
你让我自己去...
What, you-- you want me to, uh...
A型阴性  对吧
A-negative, yes?
你的血型
Your blood type?
我不知道  也许吧
Um, I don't know. Maybe.
A型阴性
A-negative,
25岁
25 years old,
70公斤
70 kilo,
身高1米8
180 centimeters.
你吸烟  喝酒
You smoke, you drink,
你不还嗑药吗
you, uh, puff, puff, puff.
啧啧啧
Tsk-tsk-tsk.
不过没有疾病  没有不良反应
But no disease, no condition,
除了有一种过敏症
no complication other than an allergy to...
等等  你别说出来
Wait. Don't say.
红霉素过敏
Erythromycin.
但我这儿有头孢唑啉  所以没关系
But I have cefazolin in here, so no problem.
你怎么知道这些的
How do you know all that?
天啊
Jesus.
他什么都想到了
He thought of everything.
0型阴性
O-negative.
这是他需要的血型
That's what he needs.
该走了
It's time to go.
麦克怎么办
What about Mike?
他带着伤  不能远行
With his injury? No. No travel.
至少要休息一周
At least a week.
我会派人来接他
I'll send for him.
你需要保护吗  古斯塔沃
我都不用猜
-多谢  -这没什么  我的朋友
- Gracias. - De nada, amigo.
祝你好运
Buena suerte.
多喝水  多休息
Water and rest.
知道
Si.
赶紧的
Vámonos.
那飞机怎么了
What happened to the plane?
去南部有很多条路可以走
There are many good ways south.
不幸的是  去北部只有一条路
Unfortunately, only one way north.
距德克萨斯州6英里
Six miles to Texas.
那边有人接应
I've got a man there
开车载我们走完剩下的路
who will drive us the rest of the way.
我还是喜欢飞机
I kind of liked the plane.
你还挺得住吗
You gonna make it?
6英里很远的
Six miles is pretty far.
我挺得住
I'll make it.
你在那边表现很好
You did well down here.
而且你证明了另一件事
And you also proved a point.
我想你现在一个人能撑得起实验室
I think you can run the lab by yourself now.
不是吗
Don't you?
放过怀特老师
Let Mr. White go.
结账还是赶人  随你
Pay him off or fire him.
不要杀他
Don't kill him.
你知道那是不可能的
You know that won't work.
那你可有麻烦了
Then you've got a problem.
我们回来了
Hi. We're home!
在写作业吗
You doing your homework?
在写
Yeah.
30分钟后开饭
Well, dinner is in about 30.
抱歉打到你家里
Hey. Sorry to call you at home,
我想你可能没收到我的信息
but I think maybe you're not getting my messages.
或者是不想跟我讲话
That, or you just don't feel like talking to me.
不管怎么说  我打电话是为了
Anyway, why I've been calling
我们之前谈的那件事
is because that thing we discussed?
我考虑过了
Well, I've been thinking, and, uh,
我决定我不能那样做
I decided I can't do it.
我知道你一定不想听到这样的消息
I know that's probably not what you wanted to hear,
但是希望你能够理解
but hopefully you'll understand,
如果你想再谈这件事
and if you wanted to talk some more about it,
也没关系
that's fine.
给我回电话  我都在
So call me. I'm all around.
请进
Come on in.
首先  你要知道我明白你的处境
First, I want to tell you that I get it.
从你讲的情况来看
From what you've told me,
沃尔特赌钱的状况
this situation with Walt's gambling
好像很严峻
sounds...intense.
没错  事态严峻
Yeah, it definitely was
而且越发棘手
and continues to be.
所以
So
如果你乐意帮忙
I would greatly appreciate it
我将非常感激
if you would just help me out here.
我已经考虑了很久
Well, I have thought long and hard about this,
现在
and, uh...
我想要这样做
here's what I want to do.
沃尔特没事吧
So is, uh, Walt gonna be okay?
你跟他有联系吗
Are you in contact with him?
他很好
Um, he's fine.
好  那就好
Good. That's good.
他还不知道你给我...
He doesn't know about you offering, uh...
对  完全不知道
No, absolutely not,
而且我也不打算让他知道
and I mean to keep it that way, so...
61万7千美元
$617,000
抬头写的我
written out to me.
什么意思
Uh, what is this?
我不能要你的钱
I can't take your money.
为什么
Oh? And why is that?
因为毕竟
Because at the end of the day,
用赌博赢来的钱去还债...
paying my debt with illicit gambling winnings...
我也说不好  就是感觉不太对
I don't know. It feels wrong.
感觉不太对
It feels wrong?
-我是这样感觉的   -嗯
-To me, it does.   -Uh-huh.
我不是对你和沃尔特有成见
I'm not judging you or Walt.
只是我心里不太舒服
I'm just saying I feel uncomfortable with it.
泰德
Well, um, Ted,
我们之所以陷入今天的困境
the whole reason we're in this mess
都是因为你让我帮你做假账
is because you had me cooking your books.
你这个始作俑者
So when did wrong
几时学会"不作恶"了
suddenly become a problem for you?
打住  当时不过是一时情急
Now, hold on. That was a one-time measure.
我当时是一心为了保护我的员工
I took an honest attempt to protect my employees
挽救我父亲的公司
and save my dad's company.
那或许是个错误
And it might've been a mistake,
可也不说明我现在应该错上加错
but that's no reason to go out and make another.
不  泰德  眼前这才是大错特错
No, Ted. This is the big mistake right here.
你欠联邦政府61万7千美金
You owe the federal government $617,000.
你不还钱  他们不会放过你
If you do not pay them, they will come after you,
然后会追查到我
and then they will come after me.
如果他们来审查我的生意
And if they audit my business,
就会发现我和沃尔特买下洗车场
find out that Walt and I paid for it
花的将近一百万美元
with close to a million dollars
都是未上税的赌博收入
in untaxed gambling winnings,
我们也会进监狱
we will go to prison,
去陪你
where you will already be.
你明白了没有
Do you understand?
我明白你很担忧
I understand you're upset,
可是你也说得太严重了
but I think you're overstating things, too.
没人会进监狱的
No one's going to prison.
我的上帝  你怎么就听不懂呢
Oh, my God. How are you not following me here?
好吧  好吧
Okay. Fine.
就假设我听了你的
Let's say I take your advice.
交上国税局的罚金  又能怎样
I pay the IRS. Then what?
你就不欠税了
Then you don't owe them.
对  可是我还欠银行钱呀  斯凯勒
Okay. But I still owe the bank, Skyler.
我还是要破产
I'm still gonna go bankrupt.
失去产业和家园
I'll lose my business and my home.
女儿们也不得不退学
I still have to pull my girls out of school.
交上那愚蠢的罚金
Just because I pay some stupid fine
丝毫不能改变我的生活已经被毁掉的事实
doesn't make my life any less ruined.
如果我没理解错的话
So, if I'm understanding you correctly,
你的意思是  你不能接受我给你的钱
you're saying you can't take the money I gave you,
但是可以接受一笔更多的钱
but you can take a larger amount.
不
No.
我只是说
I'm just saying,
尽管我非常感激
as much as I appreciate the gesture,
可是你给我的钱改变不了任何事情
the money you gave me doesn't really change anything.
-因为钱不够多吗  -不是  不是
- Because it's not enough? - No. No.
别误解我的意思
Don't twist my words.
不是钱多钱少的问题
This isn't about amounts.
而是我有我的坚持
This is about me doing the right thing.
泰德  你是在敲诈我吗
Ted, are you blackmailing me? What?
没有  没有敲诈
No. Blackmailing?
天呐
God.
我想我可能是没有说明白
I feel like I'm not explaining things right.
我看你已经说得很明白了
I think you're explaining it fine.
我注意到
I notice that, uh,
这上面的
this is for...
数额好像比我给你的少
less than what I gave you, by the way.
那是我租的奔驰
That's the Mercedes.
在我知道这钱从哪来之前租的
I leased it before I knew where the money came from.
现在你知道  你肯定要把车给还了
Mmm. And now that you know, you will, of course, be returning it?
租约蛮苛刻的
Well, the leases are pretty ironclad,
我得去看看有没有可能
so I have to see what's possible.
可是我会尽我所能的
But, yeah, I'm gonna do my best.
我会尽快还你钱的
And I will pay you back as soon as I can.
我不需要你还我  泰德
I don't want you to pay me, Ted.
我要你还给他们
I want you to pay them.
可是  斯凯...
But, Skyl--
重写一张支票
Try it again. Write a new check.
-斯凯勒  -同样的数额
- Skyler-- - Same amount.
只是这一次  把收款人
Only this time, made payable--
-我们这是怎么了  -把收款人
- What happened to us? - Make it payable
写成国家税收局
to the Internal Revenue Service.
我不能
I can't.
你必须得写
You have to.
说真的  我不能
Actually, no, I don't.
快给我写
Write it.
麻烦找索尔・古德曼
Saul Goodman, please.
告诉他事关重大
Tell him it's important.
是的
Yeah.
我做了什么
What have I done?
你好  赫克托
Hello, Hector.
他们都死了  赫克托
All of them, Hector.
伊兰迪奥先生
Don Eladio,
帕科先生  塞萨尔  罗纳尔多
Don Paco, Cesar, Renaldo,
佛托诺  思科还有路易斯
Fortuno, Cisco, and Luis,
埃斯卡纳拉
Escalara--
都死了
all dead.
你的孙子华金也死了
As is your grandson Joaquin.
你知道谁杀了华金吗
Do you know who killed Joaquin?
想见见吗
Would you like to see?
就是这个年轻人
This young man.
还记得他吗
Do you remember him?
在护送我逃跑过程中
That young man shot Joaquin to death...
这个年轻人开枪打死了华金
while I made my escape.
我记得你们之前应该见过
I believe you have met him before.
本来你们家族只剩下你和华金
It was just you and Joaquin.
你只剩下他这一个亲人
He was the only family you had left.
现在塞拉曼加家族
Now the Salamanca name
将与你一起进坟墓了
dies with you.
现在你能看我了吗
Will you look at me now?
看着我  赫克托
Look at me, Hector.
看着我
Look at me.
听着  沃尔特  我十分感谢
Hey, listen, Walt, I really appreciate
你又帮我一次
you doing this again, you know?
我知道你们最近
I know you guys must have
洗车房生意忙得不可开交
your hands full with the car wash and all.
没有  不用担心
No. No. No worries.
很乐意帮你
Happy to do it.
再说  我也有机会
Besides, it gives me a chance
能亲眼见证你的办案过程
to see how you work a case.
-还挺有趣的  -那是
- It's interesting. - Yeah.
就像在看毒品的生长过程
Like watching weeds grow, huh?
这工作无聊至极
Nah, this job's as boring as hell.
而且会一直这么下去
Until it's not.
对了
So, uh,
在墨西哥的那事怎么样了
any more news on that thing in Mexico?
还是老样子
Aah, same old, same old.
就是一群禽兽互相挖空对方的眼睛
Bunch of animals clawing each other's eyes out over turf.
你觉得所有的死者
So you think all the victims
都是贩毒集团的成员
were cartel members?
你还是知道的少点好
Not in the loop enough to know.
听着  能在这条街右转吗
Listen, take a right at this street here, will you?
右转  可我们要去养鸡场
A right? But, uh, we're going to the chicken farm.
那可在正前方
That's straight ahead.
不了  今天我们绕点路
No. Gonna take a little detour.
好吧
All right.
那里有一个
Yeah, there's this, uh,
洗衣厂我要去检查一下
industrial laundry I want to check out.
不太远
It's not far.
在这里右转
Just turn right here.
什么洗衣厂
What, uh-- What-- What laundry?
什么来头
What about it?
那是名叫麦德罗电机公司的下属企业
Well, it's owned by this company-- this Madrigal Electromotive.
这是个大型德国企业集团  涉猎很广
It's this big German conglomerate. Into everything.
可事实表明
Well, it turns out
那家集团也拥有福林炸鸡店
it's the same company that owns Fring's chicken joints.
感觉你在胡乱猜测呢
Sounds like a real shot in the dark there.
我是说  你自己说的
I mean, you said it yourself.
要是这个麦德罗  名字对吧
If this-- Madrigal, is it?
要是这是一家大集团  那么
If it's such a big conglomerate, then--
他们肯定涉及各种行业
I mean, they must own all kinds of businesses.
这只是
Nah, it just...
只是听上去理由有点单薄
It just sounds kind of...thin.
看看你  你剃了头发
Well, look at you. You lose your hair,
进行了几次侦察
you go on a couple stakeouts.
就认为自己是大侦探科杰克了
So now you're what, Kojak?
我只是说说而已
I'm just saying.
再说那个养鸡场
Now, the chicken farm, however--
那地方看上去是一个
boy, that place seems ripe
十分合适做地下活动的地方
for some kind of, uh, clandestine activity.
我只是不想错过任何线索
I just-- I just don't want us to miss anything, you know?
你想说地下活动
Yeah, well, you want to talk about clandestine activity?
麦德罗电机同时还拥有一家
Madrigal Electromotive also owns a subsidiary
生产最先进空气过滤系统的附属企业
that manufactures this state-of-the-art air filtration system.
恰恰正是盖尔・伯蒂彻
And none other than Gale Boetticher
订了其中一个系统
took delivery of one of these systems.
一个有着计划建造一个
Yeah, a chemist who was in possession
大型冰毒实验室的化学家
of hand-drawn plans for a meth super-lab,
恰恰又在被爆头的几天前
and was visited by none other that Gus Fring
正好被古斯・福林拜访过
just days before he was capped in the face, okay?
这开始有点像
Shit, this is starting to feel like a--
《英雄不流泪》里面的剧情了
like Three Days on the Condor, you know?
无论如何  一个洗衣厂正是
Anyway, an industrial laundry would be one hell of a place
隐藏冰毒实验室的好地方
to hide a-- hide a meth lab.
就在那里
There it is right up there.
这个口转弯
Just turn in there.
慢下来  你得转弯了  沃尔特
Well, slow down. You gotta turn there, Walt.
沃尔特  你在干吗  你刚开过了
Walt, what are you doing? You just missed it.
对不起  那里看上去像条泥路
I'm sorry. It looked like a dirt road.
我以为你要接着开
I thought you meant further up.
就这里调头吧
Just bang a U-ie over here.
真不赖  谢谢你们
Mmm. Hits the spot. Thanks, guys.
我和妈妈说要冰激淋
I said to Mom, "Ice cream,"
可她说这个味道差不多  还更健康
but she was like, "It tastes the same, and it's healthier."
不好意思  我尽力了
So, sorry. I tried.
冻酸奶完全一个味道啊
Frozen yogurt does taste the same.
吃起来没一点差别
Tastes exactly the same.
真替你的味蕾难过
I feel, like, sorry for your taste buds.
汉克姨夫  你说说看
Weigh in here, Uncle Hank.
又不要钱嘛  不要钱的东西都好吃
Hey, it's free food. Free food always tastes good.
不要钱的酒我更喜欢
Free drinks even better.
亲爱的
Hey, honey.
又来个看你的  能行吗
Can you handle another visitor?
脱线先生你好啊
Ho-ho! Mister Magoo.
[以超级近视闻名的电影人物]
-有何指教  -小心看路
- Yeah, sure. - Hey, watch out.
可别撞墙上了  知道不
Don't run into any walls or anything, all right?
没问题
Okay.
老爸
Hey, Dad.
儿子
Hey, son.
戴着这个感觉如何  汉克
So how you feeling, Hank?
感觉就跟戴了一狗脖套似的
Kind of feels like one of those cones they put on dogs
就是防止狗狗舔蛋的那玩意
so they don't lick their own balls.
谢了  你真会说  继续
Nice. Thank you. Stay classy.
不过你也别挂心
Anyway, hanging in there.
你来看我  我很高兴
Glad you stopped by.
我...这件事真是对不住你
Listen, I'm-- I'm sorry about all this.
那家伙也不知哪儿蹦出来的
That guy-- he just came out of nowhere.
才怪  哪是蹦出来的
Yeah, actually, he didn't.
一英里外我就瞧见他了
I saw him coming a mile away.
行  全当我脑子进水了吧
Hey, just mark it down as a brain fart,
好在没出人命
and be thankful no one got killed.
我跟你说
Well, I'll tell you one thing.
你们的二人组任务到此为止
Your Hardy Boys routine is over.
不许再让他带你去搞侦查
No more asking him to drive you on stakeouts.
太危险了  听到了吗
It's too dangerous. You hear me?
-那我来  -不  不行
- I'll do it. - Oh, no, you won't.
玛丽说的对  是我鼠目寸光
Marie's right. It was a bit shortsighted of me.
所以我认栽了
That's why I caved.
认什么栽
Caved?
我残疾了
I broke down.
我订了一辆"残的"
I ordered me a gimp-mobile.
能不能别用这个词
I wish you would stop calling it that.
什么意思  带升降机的微型车吗
What do you mean, like a handi-van with a lift?
不是  就是那种普通款泰虎
Nah, nah. It's a regular Tahoe.
带手控的
It's got hand controls.
我下了单  大概一个星期就能到货
I ordered it. It should be here in about a week.
虽然不愿意常开那玩意
I don't expect to be in it long,
不过总得自己出门
but I gotta get around on my own
别总给大家当累赘
and stop being such a damn burden to everyone.
失陪一下
Oh. Sorry.
洗车场的事
Car wash business.
是我  方便讲话吗
Hey, it's me. Can you talk?
你说吧
I can listen.
好吧  他没有枪
Fair enough. He doesn't own a gun.
至少没有合法购买的枪支
At least not one that he bought legally.
家里的安保系统也没装
Nor does his home security system
那类紧急救援按钮装置
have any kind of panic button arrangement.
所以依我看  可以过去搞了
So, way I see it, we're good to go.
主要看你是不是还想这样处理
That is, if this is still how you want to handle it.
我说过了  不想任何人受到伤害
Like I said, I don't want anyone hurt.
对他唯一的要求就是开出支票
All I want is for him to write a check.
放心好了
Yeah. It's gonna be fine.
我派我最得意的手下搞定
I've got my A-team on it.
有什么可以效劳的吗
Can I help you?
有  谢谢
Yeah. Thanks.
你们不能就这么...
You just can't...
究竟什么情况
What's this about?
贝内克先生  告诉你什么情况
I'll tell you what this is about, Mr. Beneke.
情况就是你得和我尽量把修尔伺候高兴了
This is about you and me doing our best to keep Huell happy.
修尔  谁是修尔
Huell? Who's Huell?
这位就是
This is Huell.
修尔  你高兴吗
Huell, you happy?
一般般
Reasonably.
什么惹你不高兴了
What would make you unhappy?
这个小王八蛋不听话
This little mofo not doing what he's told.
那要是你还不高兴
And if you were to become unhappy,
贝内克先生敢不管吗
Mr. Beneke wouldn't care for that?
量他也不敢
I'm gonna say no.
好了  现在你明白了
Well, there you have it.
赶紧去拿支票簿
Let's go find your checkbook.
行了吗  走吧  好嘞
Ready? Here we go. All right.
咱走着  迈开步子
We're walking, we're swinging our feet.
就这样  很好
There you go. Very nice.
你这房子还不赖啊  这边
Beautiful place you have here. This way.
听好了  一共是617,226美元...
So, the amount's gonna be for $617,226--
我可没有那么多钱
I don't have anywhere near that kind of money.
少来这套
Hold that thought.
忘说了  我们知道你账户里有多少
Forgot to mention we know exactly, down to the penny,
一个子儿都瞒不了
how much money's in your checking account.
现在明白了吗
Okay? Understand?
还想说刚才那套鬼话吗
You still want to say that stuff from before?
大概不敢了吧
Maybe not. So,
617,226块
$617,226
外加3毛1分
and 31 cents,
开给国税局
made payable to the Internal Revenue Service.
什么
W-What?
等等  这是斯凯勒
Wait. This is, uh, Skyler's...
斯凯勒・怀特派你们来的
Skyler White sent you?
谁派我们来并不重要
Doesn't matter who sent us. For right now,
现在你唯一该操心的是手里那个
all you have to do is worry about that.
天呐  这可是大水冲了龙王庙了
Oh, my God. This is a giant misunderstanding.
斯凯勒是我非常好的朋友  知道吗
Skyler is a dear friend of mine, all right?
让我给她打个电话  我们就...
Let me call her. We'll, uh...
慢着  贝内克先生  你搞错了
No, you're misunderstanding, Mr. Beneke.
打电话已经晚了  现在得开支票了
Phone-call time is over. This is check-writing time.
简直疯了  斯凯勒绝不会这样对我的
This is crazy. Skyler would never do this to me.
赶紧坐下  开支票
Sit down and write!
这就对了
There you go.
617,226美元
$617,226
31美分
and 31...
很好
Yeah. Right.
这才听话嘛
You got it.
修尔  现在高兴了吗
Huell, you happy?
修尔高兴了
Huell's happy.
好吧
All right.
别的我们都帮你填写好了
Everything else has been filled out for you.
我们只需要
All's we need
你在这里
is a signature
签个名
right there.
很好
Great.
困难的都做完了
Hard part's over.
接下来
Here's what happens next.
修尔留在这里陪你
Huell's gonna hang here with you.
我争取在五点之前
I'm gonna make sure I get this down to UPS
把这个寄出去
before 5 o'clock.
回来的路上买点三明治
On the way back, I'm gonna grab some sandwiches.
然后接下来的几天  咱们三个
The three of us can hang out,
可以一起打打牌  看看电视什么的
play cards or watch TV or whatever
直到你的支票兑现为止
for the next couple of days until the check clears.
没问题吧
Painless, right?
除非你这连有线电视都没有
Unless you don't have cable,
那可就糟透了
in which case is gonna suck.
那么
So...
非得让我躲在脏布堆里吗
Does the laundry have to be dirty?
不是
Nope.
有人在这里制过毒
Someone cooked here.
你失踪了四天
You've been out of commission four days.
你以为没了你
Think we're gonna shut down the whole operation
我们就不开工了吗
just for you?
是谁  谁制的毒
Who cooked? Who was here?
那些后空翻是怎么做出来得
Now, how are you doing all those backflips?
-告诉我  -小子
- Tell me. - Chico.
我要追上你了
Oh. Oh, I'm gonna get you.
要追上了
Oh, I'm gonna get you.
跳
Jump.
按动手柄
You're just pressing buttons,
就能玩出各种花样
and it makes you do magical stuff.
-才不是  -就是
- No. - Yes.
你作弊
Cheater.
谁赢了
Who's winning?
我
I...
看看你  看看
Look at you. Look at...
-我做了101次后空翻  -你
- 101 backflips I did. - Oh, you.
你先替我玩
Hey, keep it going.
放松  放轻松
Relax, relax.
你麻烦大了
Oh, you're in trouble.
老妈出马
Mama's in the house.
杰西
Jesse.
干什么  我很忙
What do you want? I'm busy.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
我没话和你说
I got nothing to say to you, man.
杰西  求你了  我很抱歉
Jesse, please. I'm sorry.
一分钟  只要一分钟
Just one minute. That's all I ask.
从这里滚出去
Get the hell outta my house.
滚
Come on.
给我一分钟
Just give me one minute!
听我解释
Let me just explain myself here.
好吧  听我
Okay. Let me--
闭嘴
Shh! Shut up.
好  好
All right. All right. Okay. Okay.
我很抱歉
All right. I'm sorry.
我知道
I know
你在一个人制毒
that you have been cooking without me.
是啊  所以呢
That's right. So what?
"所以呢"
"So what"?
你说呢  难道你看不出
Isn't it obvious to you
古斯在打什么主意吗
what Gus is planning?
他想让你代替我
He's going to use you to replace me.
他觉得你不再需要我了
He doesn't think you need me anymore.
杰西
Jesse--
杰西  如果你同意取代我的话
Jesse, if you agree to replace me,
他会杀了我的
he will kill me.
你把你的连襟带到了实验室
You brought your brother-in-law to our lab.
你他妈的有毛病啊
What the hell's wrong with you?
那不是我的错  杰西  求你了
That's not my fault. Jesse, please--
杰西 听我说
OK, look, Jesse
你得帮我  求你了
You gotta help me. Please.
上一次我找你帮忙的时候
The last time I asked for your help,
你对我说
you said
"希望我被装进塑料桶“
"I hope you end up buried
”埋在墨西哥的沙漠里"
in a barrel in the Mexican desert."
你完了
You are done.
被炒了
Fired.
不要再去实验室
Do not show your face at the laundry again.
远离平克曼
Stay away from Pinkman.
永远
Do not go near him.
不要靠近他一步
Ever.
听见了吗
Are you listening to me?
不然怎样
Or else you'll do what?
你说什么
What did you say?
远离平克曼
Stay away from Pinkman...
不然的话
or else you'll do...
你要怎样
what?
杀了我
Kill me?
如果你能杀我
If you could kill me,
你早就下手了
I'd already be dead.
但你不能
But you can't.
你不能杀我
You can't kill me
因为如果你杀了我
because Jesse wouldn't cook for you
杰西就不会帮你制毒
if you did.
对不对
That's it, isn't it?
尽管你千方百计挑拨我们反目
No matter how hard you tried to turn him against me,
给他洗脑
screw with his head
让他恨我
so that he would hate my guts,
可他还是
and he still...
不许你杀我
won't let you do it.
暂时而已
For now.
他会想通的
But he'll come around.
同时  你连襟的问题
In the meantime, there's the matter of your brother-in-law.
你承诺过会解决的
He is a problem you promised to resolve.
但你失败了
You have failed.
现在轮到我来对付他了
Now it's left to me to deal with him.
不行
You can't--
如果你胆敢阻拦我
If you try to interfere,
那问题就会简单多了
this becomes a much simpler matter.
我会杀了你老婆
I will kill your wife.
你儿子
I will kill your son.
还有你那刚出生的女儿
I will kill your infant daughter.
太棒了
Great.
这下可好  我才刚跟她说
Perfect, you know. This is just...
你们是我最得意的手下
I told her you were my A-team.
那是天意
It was an act of God.
天意不可违啊
Ain't no accounting for no act of God.
至少支票已经寄出去了
Check's in the mail, at least.
你好  怀特夫人
Oh, hello, Mrs. White.
好消息是国税局的帐已经付清了
The good news is the IRS has been paid off.
坏消息是
The bad news is...
天呐
Jesus!
不管那么多了
Well, here goes nothing.
悠着点
Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa! Slow down!
-怎么回事  -索尔
- What the... - Saul.
你怎么听说的
How did you hear?
什么  听说什么
What? H-Hear what?
伙计们  出去  出去
Uh, guys, go, go, go.
赶紧走
Scram. Wh--
-你到底出什么事了  -索尔  索尔
- What the hell happened to you? - Saul, Saul,
你之前跟我提过的那个人
this man that we spoke of before--
你说这个人
this-- this person that you said
能帮我消失  让我过上崭新的生活
could-- could disappear me, give me a whole new life--
-对  -还能确保我永远不被发现
- Yeah. - and make sure that I'm never found.
-对  -我需要他
- Yeah. - I need him.
索尔  古斯准备杀我全家
Saul, Gus is gonna murder my whole family.
天啊
Oh, Christ.
我现在就需要他
I need this man now.
-索尔  立马就要  -索尔  -好  好
- Saul! Now, Saul! - Yeah, yeah.
你应该明白这可没有回头路
You understand there's no coming back from this?
你会得到新的社保号码和新的身份证
You're gonna get new Socials and new identities.
不可以再联系朋友或亲戚
You can't contact your friends or relatives ever again.
好的  当然  我明白
All right. Yes, yes, I understand.
你怎么说服
How are you gonna sell this
你妻子和你十几岁的儿子
to that wife of yours and your teenage son?
我别无选择
I have got no choice.
有极端危险分子想要你的命
You're wanted by some pretty scary individuals,
再加上法网难逃
not to mention the law.
你属于个高危顾客
You're a high-risk client.
得用顶配服务才行
You're gonna need the deluxe service.
-需要花费...  -多少钱
- It's gonna cost you. - How much?
我最后一次得到的顶配报价是12万5千
The last quote I got on the deluxe was 125 grand.
你有四个人需要消失掉
But you got four people to vanish.
至少得50万才行
It's gonna be at least half a million.
-而且他只收现金  -我有现金  赶紧
- And he accepts cash only. - I've got the money. Now come on.
-拜托  -给
- Please! - Here.
好
Okay.
这是一家吸尘器修理公司
This-- This is a vacuum cleaner repair company.
你以为会是什么名头  伊斯兰快速藏匿公司不成
What'd you expect, Haji's Quick-Vanish?
我根本不知道这人的名字
I don't even know the guy's name.
你只要打那个号码  然后留言
You just call that number and you leave a message.
告诉他们你需要一个新的吸尘器
You tell them that you need a new dust filter
要胡佛牌增压式大功率吸尘器  型号60
for a Hoover MaxExtract Pressure-Pro, Model 60.
我都写在上面了  他会在五分钟后回电
I wrote it right on there. He'll call you back in five minutes.
好的  可以
Okay. Okay, fine.
他要多久能打点好
How long does it take for him to arrange?
这家伙速度很快  你现在生死攸关
The guy works fast. I mean, that's the game here.
得赶紧让你全家收拾好
You gotta have your family packed
在你打电话前都准备好出发
and ready to go before you make the call.
他会告诉你见面地点
He'll tell you where to meet him.
万事具备前他会把你妥善安置
He'll put you up in a safe house until everything is set.
可你得带好现金
But you gotta bring the money.
他没全额收款前是不会出一分力的
He doesn't lift a finger unless he's paid in full.
好
Okay.
-索尔  -我不能说这是我的荣幸
- Saul - Can't say it's been a pleasure,
-可  -我要你再为我做一件事
- but-- - I need you to do one more thing for me.
你得打电话到毒品管制局
You need to call the DEA,
你得告诉他们古斯要对汉克下手
and you need to tell them that Gus has a hit out on Hank.
不  你一定得帮我
No, you have to do it for me.
兄弟  我还要在这儿混呢
Buddy, I gotta go on living here.
我活得很爽  还不想寻死
I'm way too comfortable in my wingtips-
那就打匿名电话
Just call anonymous then.
-你去打匿名电话  -不行  不行
- You call anonymously! - I can't! I can't!
我是半个毒品管制局的人
I'm practically in the DEA family.
连圣诞晚会都去过  求你了
I go to their Christmas parties, for Christ's sake.
他们认识我  听得出我的声音  会露馅的
They know me. They know my voice. They'll know me.
求你了  为我办这件事吧  求你了
Please, you gotta do it for me. I'm begging you.
-求你了  求你了  -不
- Please. Please. -No.
我连襟不该因此受牵连而死
My brother-in-law doesn't deserve to die because of this.
-我决不能提到古斯  -成
- There's no way I'm mentioning Gus. - Okay.
我顶多说是贩毒集团
The best I'll go-- I'll say it's the cartel.
他们要回来把没办利索的活搞定
They're coming back to finish the job that they botched.
随你怎么说
You say whatever you have to say.
只要给我一个小时
You just give me an hour to c--
我得去接我老婆孩子
I-- I need to collect my wife and kids.
好吗  只要给我一小时
Okay? Just give me an hour,
然后你就打电话
and then you make the phone call.
别忘了  拜托
Don't forget. Please.
好
Yeah.
谢谢  索尔
Thank you, Saul.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no.
其余的钱呢
Where's the rest?
不够  不够
That's not enough. That's not enough.
-沃尔特  -在下面
- Walt? - Down here!
沃尔特  你那通电话是什么意思
Walt, what did that phone call mean?
在哪里
Where is it?
其余的呢
Where's the rest?
钱呢  斯凯勒  其余的钱呢
The money, Skyler. Where is the rest?
斯凯勒  钱去哪儿了
Skyler, where is the money?
我给泰德了
I gave it to Ted.
什么  你干什么了
What? You-- You did what?
沃尔特
Walt, I'm--
我也没办法
I had to.
我也是为了我们  为了这个家
For us, for the family.
我发誓  沃尔特
I swear, Walt.
你把钱给了贝内克
You gave our money to Beneke?
沃尔特  求你  求你  听我说完
Walt, please, please, just hear me out.
求你了
Please!
沃尔特
Walt?
你好  这里是怀特家
Hi. You've reached the White family.
请留言
Please leave a message.
斯凯特
Skyler?
又来了
It's happening again.
毒品管制局打电话来
The DEA called. They got some tip
他们接到线报
from an informant that
贩毒集团要杀汉克
the cartel-- they want to kill Hank!
天呐
Oh, God.
他们正派探员
They're sending agents to--
到我家来保护我们
to our house right now to guard us.
天呐
God!
什么时候才能结束
When is this going to end?
玛丽  我在呢
Marie, I'm here.
我在呢
I'm here.
给我具体说说
Tell me exactly what happened.